Preliminary Guide to the Robert Edward Dawson Papers, 1939-1998
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Robert Edward Dawson papers 1939-1998
Dawson, Robert Edward, 1918-
46.1. linear feet Extent: 25,113 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00294
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Robert Edward Dawson Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift, 2000-2001.
Biographical Note
African-American ophthalmologist and citizen of Durham (Durham Co.), N.C. Born on February 23,1918 in Rocky Mount, N.C., Dawson received his B.S. from Clark College inAtlanta, Ga., and his M.D. from Meharry Medical College in Nashville, Tenn.
Collection Overview
This collection documents Dawson's professional and civic life.Materials include scrapbooks; reports; subject files; memoranda; andcorrespondence, in particular from prominent Durhamites, such as Floyd B.McKissick, Sr., and James E. Shepard. The collection details Dawson's medicalpractices, teaching, and board memberships at Lincoln Community Health Center, Lincoln Hospital, and Durham County General Hospital. It also documentshis lengthy and high-level involvement with the following institutions andorganizations: Meharry Medical College, George W. Hubbard Hospital, the National Medical Society, the National Society for the Prevention of Blindness,the North Carolina Society for the Prevention ofBlindness, the Old North State Medical Society, North Carolina Central University, and the Mutual Savings & Loan Association. Thecollection also contains 35 color photographs and 48 negatives. Acquired aspart of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African AmericanDocumentation. (1939-1998) (11,550 items) (19.00 lf) (acc#00-320)
The addition to the collection contains financial materials,correspondence, memoranda, newspaper clippings and magazine articles (8560items, 1946-1997), and photographs (300 items) that continue to documentDawson's medical career and his involvement in organizations in Durham, NorthCarolina, and nationally. In addition to the institutions, hospitals, medicalpractices, and civic groups that have been described in the first accession,this addition includes materials from Dawson's real estate ventures. Theseinclude owning apartments with the firms Dawson and Watts and then Dawson, Watts and Cleland (1970s) and buildingapartments with the firm Century Oaks, Ltd. (1977-1981). The majority ofthe 2 black-and-white and 297 color photographs appear to be of family. Onetintype is included of an unidentified woman wearing what may be a weddingdress (undated). (8860 items) (14.50 lf) (2001-73)
The addition to the collection (4703 items, dated 1946-1996 and n. d.,bulk date 1998-1994, 12.60 linear feet) includes subject files holding reports,memoranda, correspondence, and printed material, as well as many business andpersonal financial records. In addition, there are two color photographs.(01-153)
Subject Headings
Dawson, Robert Edward, 1918-; McKissick, Floyd B. (Floyd Bixler), 1922-; Shepard, James Edward; Meharry Medical College; North Carolina Central University; National Medical Association (U.S.); National Society to Prevent Blindness; Dawson and Watts; Dawson, Watts and Cleland; Century Oaks, Ltd; African American physicians -- North Carolina; Ophthalmologists; African Americans in the professions; African American universities and colleges; Hospitals -- North Carolina; Savings and loan associations -- North Carolina; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Clippings; Negatives; Scrapbooks; Tintype; John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African-American Documentation
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2000-0320
  Attention: Collection is restricted. Patrons must sign a release form regarding privacy rights. Contact Technical Services.
  - Medical Records-Private Practice (Lincoln Community Health Center, 1969- ) (Box 1)
  - Lincoln Hospital departmental records (Box 1)
  - Lincoln Hospital committee and administrative records (Box 1)
  - Business records (Box 1)
  - Brochures/Publications ( National Medical Association/Medical-related) (Box 1)
  - Proposal Durham County Hospital Corporation Affirmative Action Plan-December 1984 (Box 1)
  - Personal correspondence (Box 1)
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Map (Box 1)
  - Meharry Medical School files (Box 1)
  - Dawson's children's school records (Box 1)
  - Correspondence ( 1979-1983) (Box 2)
  - Financial records (Box 2)
  - Personal medical information (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous files (Box 2)
  - Map (Box 2)
  - Various Hospital Financial/ Staff Concerns (Box 2)
  - Meharry Medical College files (incl. Bulletins) (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Community Health Center files (Private Clinic Proposal) (Box 2)
  - Floyd B. McKissick writings (Box 2)
  - George W. Hubbard Hospital at Meharry Medical College files (Box 2)
  - Meharry Medical College files (Box 3)
    - Board of Management of Alumni Association files (Box 3)
    - Board of Trustees reports (Box 3)
    - George W. Hubbard Hospital files (Box 3)
    - Constitution and By-laws (Box 3)
    - Alumni Association Presidency, Committee, and miscellaneous files (Box 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Lincoln Community Health Center files (Box 3)
  - Photo with negatives (Meharry Class of 1943 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Articles of Incorporation of Durham County Hospital Corporation ( June 21, 1971) (Box 3)
  - American Medical Association (House of Delegates Handbook 1980) (Box 3)
  - National Medical Association Convention (1979) files (Box 3)
  - National Medical Association (NMA) files (Box 4)
    - Journals and Annual Reports (Box 4)
    - Insurance Program/ Committee (Box 4)
    - Board of Trustees 1975 (Box 4)
    - Council of Scientific Assembly (Box 4)
    - Ophthalmology (Box 4)
    - Handbook for the Auxiliary to the NMA (Box 4)
    - House of Delegates (minutes) (Box 4)
    - Retirement Plan Trust (Box 4)
    - Management Committee (Box 4)
    - Project 75 (Box 4)
  - Clippings (Box 4)
  - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness files (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Society for the Prevention of Blindness, Inc. files (Box 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - American Cancer Society files ( 1964-; Annual Reports) (Box 4)
  - National Medical Association (NMA) files (Box 5)
    - Board of Trustees 1973-1975 (Box 5)
    - Time and Place Committee (Box 5)
    - E.E.N.T. Section (Box 5)
    - Constitution Committee (Box 5)
    - Awards Committee (Box 5)
    - Black Congress on Health andLaw (Box 5)
    - Financial Aid for Students (Box 5)
    - Letters/Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Task Force (Box 5)
    - Activities of the President (Box 5)
    - Planning and Development (Box 5)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness files (Box 5)
  - Old North State Medical Society files (Box 6)
  - American Hospital Association files (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College Trustees' Manual (Box 6)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 6)
  - North Carolina College Health Service (present-day North Carolina Central University) files (Box 7)
  - Lincoln Community Health Hospital files (Box 7)
  - Correspondence (incl. James E. Shepard, founder of North Carolina Central University) (Box 7)
  - Old North Medical Society files (Box 7)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation files (Box 7)
    - Development Committee (Box 7)
    - Board of Trustees (Box 7)
  - Durham County General Hospital files (Box 7)
    - Constitution and By-laws (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous files (Box 7)
  - Speeches (Box 8)
  - News Articles of Interest (Box 8)
  - Correspondence (Box 8)
  - Meharry Medical College (Box 8)
  - National Medical Association (Box 8)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness (Box 8)
  - American Medical Association (Box 8)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association (Box 9)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness (Box 9)
  - Meharry Medical College Fundraising Campaign (Box 9)
  - Graduate degree problems in counseling at North Carolina Central University, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Some personal financial and biographical information (Box 9)
  - National Medical Association, Continuing Medical Education (Box 9)
  - Meharry Medical College and George W. Hubbard Hospital (Box 9)
  - NCCU Board of Trustees (Box 9)
  - Other groups in which Dawson participated (Box 9)
    Including the Congressional Black Caucus Health Brain Trust and the State of North Carolina, Department of Human Resources, Medical Care Advisory Committee
  - Meharry Medical College alumni materials, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
    [One folder includes sensitive material-student grades]
  - Rites of Passage ( S.A.G.E. Project) for African American Males (Box 10)
  - NMA Black Caucus and NCCU Nursing School, 1969 (Box 10)
  - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness (Box 10)
  - Durham County General Hospital (Box 10)
  - National Medical Association, including the Blue Ribbon Task Force (Box 10)
  - Greensboro College (Box 10)
  - Examples of reminder/overdue bill letters (Box 10)
  - Meharry Medical College Board of Trustees (Box 10)
  - Meharry Medical College Executive Committee (Box 10)
  - Meharry Medical College Alumni Association (Box 10)
  - Durham County General Hospital (Box 11)
  - Meharry Medical College and George W. Hubbard Hospital (Box 11)
  - North Carolina Central University (Box 11)
  - National Medical Association (Box 11)
  - Mutual Savings and Loan Association (Box 11)
  - [Building construction records] (Box 11)
  - North Carolina Central University (Box 11)
  - [Financial materials from office, ca. 1980s} (Box 11)
  - [Loose professional correspondence, ca. 1980s] (Box 11)
  - Photographs (Box 11)
  - Old North State Medical Society (Box 12)
  - NCNB Educational Loan and other account and Robert Dawson, Jr. loan (Box 12)
  - National Conference on Trusteeship, Association of Governing Boards of Universities and Colleges (Box 12)
  - Washington Duke Ambassador's Club (Box 12)
  - Curriculum vitae (Box 12)
  - [ Arthur Boyd's case before the NC Medical Examiner's Board, 1986] (Box 12)
  - Black Community Forum (Box 12)
  - Brown, Roland (Box 12)
  - Guardsmen, Inc., ca. 1960s (Box 12)
  - Lectures-Nursing Class, ca. 1960 (Box 12)
    [includes sensitive material: student grades]
  - Articles of Interest (Abstracts, etc.), 1956-1958 and 1980s-1990s (Box 12)
  - Oversize materials, Miscellaneous items from boxes 1-3 (Box 13)
    Includes correspondence and clippings.
  - Miscellaneous items from boxes 4-7 (Box 14)
    Includes clippings.
- Accession 2001-0073 (Box 14)
  Attention: Collection is restricted and contains sensitive information throughout. Users must sign release form regarding privacy rights. Contact Technical Services.
  - Medical/Professional Files (Box 1)
    - Gray, Willie (Box 1)
    - Grievance Committee (Box 1)
    - DCGH (Box 1)
    - American Board OPHTH (Box 1)
    - American Op. Contact Lens (Box 1)
    - Continuing Medical Education (Box 1)
    - Duke University (Box 1)
    - DCGH (Box 1)
    - Department of Health and Human Services (Box 1)
    - Duke University, Physician's AssociateProgram (Box 1)
    - Dr. John Merritt (Box 1)
  - Airline Schedules (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Financial, Tax, and Property Records, (12 folders) (Box 1)
  - Medical/Professional Files (Box 2)
    - Diseases, Glaucoma (Box 2)
    - Eye therapy (Box 2)
    - Dudley, Charles R. (Box 2)
    - John Hancock Vision Plan (Box 2)
    - John Joyner- NMA (Box 2)
    - Vision Care (Box 2)
    - Vision Care Contracts, Aetna Insurance (Box 2)
    - Cont. Med. Education (Box 2)
    - Arthur Boyd (Box 2)
    - Quiglas Milton, M.D. (Box 2)
    - Letters-pick up glasses (Box 2)
    - Charles E. McClinton, Ph.D. (Box 2)
    - Old North State Medical (Box 2)
    - National Society to PreventBlindness (Box 2)
  - Uzzle Motor Co. (Box 2)
  - Windowman (Box 2)
  - Computers Information (Box 2)
  - Carolina Motor Club (Box 2)
  - Blk Man (Box 2)
  - Marriott (Box 2)
  - Marriott's Club Marquis (Box 2)
  - Financial, Tax, Property Records (Box 2)
    - Amoco (Box 2)
    - The Gold Card (Box 2)
    - Mastercard-closed accounts (Box 2)
    - Insurance, Massachusetts Mutual Life (Box 2)
    - Union Insurance and Realty (Box 2)
    - NCNB (Box 2)
    - Credit Records (Box 2)
    - A. Bord (Box 2)
    - Thomas, Knight, Trent, King, andCompany (Box 2)
    - Humphrey Analyzer (Box 2)
    - Fidelity Investments (Box 2)
    - Dean Witter (Box 2)
    - Bobby 1987 (Box 2)
    - Insurance (Box 2)
    - Financial Planning (Box 2)
    - Randall Miller Corporate (Box 2)
    - Medical Mutual (Box 2)
    - R.E. Dawson, M.D. P.A. (Box 2)
    - Perry, Dwight (Box 2)
    - Dawson-Perry (Box 2)
  - Tintype of unidentified woman in [wedding dress], undated (Box 2)
  - Financial, Tax, and Property Records (Box 3)
    - Canon--Uni-copy (Box 3)
    - Watts, Cleland, and Dawson (Box 3)
    - IBM--typewriter material (Box 3)
    - Bank- Mechanics and Farmers (Box 3)
    - Quarterly Report Copies, 1977January-December (Box 3)
    - Unemployment Taxes 1979 (Box 3)
    - Tom Gilmore, Deputy Secretary, Department of Human Resources (Box 3)
    - Income Tax (General) (Box 3)
    - Kehoe Plan (Box 3)
    - Contributions (Box 3)
    - Garrett, Sullivan, etc. (Box 3)
    - Mrs. Mary C. Jones (Box 3)
    - Contracts - Equipment (Box 3)
    - Collection Tips (Box 3)
    - Chapel Hill, Carboro Project (Box 3)
    - Insurance and Finance (Box 3)
  - Association, Membership, and Committee Records (Box 3)
    - Eye-Bank Association ofAmerica (Box 3)
    - EDSF, Standing Committee of Physician Consultants (Box 3)
    - Assoc. Gov. Boards, Task Force (Box 3)
    - Alpha Omega Alpha (Box 3)
    - Association of GoverningBoards (Box 3)
    - Better Health Foundation (Box 3)
    - Carolina Motor Club (Box 3)
    - Commission for the Blind (correspondence) (Box 3)
    - Meharry Medical College Board of Trustees (Box 3)
    - Addresses, Misc. Organizations (Box 3)
  - Medical/Professional Files (Box 3)
    - DCGH Directory (Box 3)
    - EDS Federal (Box 3)
    - [Opthalmology Seminar] (Box 3)
    - Employee Folder (Box 3)
    - AMA/ NMA joint liaison (Box 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Letters 1976, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Letters 1994, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Letters 1970-1971 (Box 3)
    - Letters 1975 (Box 3)
  - Employment of the Handicapped (Box 3)
  - Advertising Firms (Box 3)
  - Clark College, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Addresses, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Speeches (Box 4)
  - Clippings (Box 4)
  - Personal and Professional Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Memoirs (Box 4)
  - Memorabilia (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook (Box 4)
  - Photographs, (6 folders) (Box 4)
  - National Medical Association, House of Delegates Handbook, (4 folders) (Box 4)
  - Hubbard Hospital Survey, 1978 (Box 4)
  - 97th Annual Convention of the Old North State Medical Society Folder (Box 4)
  - Old North State Medical Society (Box 4)
  - Finances and Investments, (4 folders) (Box 4)
  - Newsletters/Newspapers/Magazines/Clippings/Brochures, (6 folders) (Box 4)
  - Mauphin - Meharry Medical College (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Computer Printout (Box 4)
  - Ruth Dudley - bills (Box 4)
  - Memorandums (Box 4)
  - Church programs for various events (Box 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Conventions (Box 5)
  - Black Americans and Higher Education (Box 5)
  - Durham Hospital-Laboratory Medicine (Box 5)
  - Addresses (Box 5)
  - Hospital Board Trustee Information (Box 5)
  - Papers (Box 5)
  - Ocular Bacteriology (Box 5)
  - Annual Report of the National Medical Association, 1972-1973 (Box 5)
  - Lincoln Community Health Center (Box 5)
  - Health Themes of NMA to Secretary of Health (Box 5)
  - University of North Carolina (Box 5)
  - Durham Ambulatory Services (Box 5)
  - License - N.C. Department of Revenue, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Record of Laser Treatment, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Planning Financial Service (Box 5)
  - Guardsman (Box 5)
  - Melanie Dawson (Box 5)
  - Educational - Youth Leadership Program (Box 5)
  - American Cancer Society, 1953-1963 (Box 5)
  - N.C. Chapter of the American College of Surgeons (Box 5)
  - North Carolina State Commission for the Blind (Box 5)
  - Durham Chamber of Commerce-Community Development Committee (Box 5)
  - Diabetic Retinopathy Study (Box 5)
  - District Court of Durham (Box 5)
  - Disability Insurance (Box 5)
  - Division of Disability Determination (Box 5)
  - Durham Chamber of Commerce (Box 5)
  - Mutual Savings and Loan Association - Board of Trustees, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Medicare, Medicaid, and Private Fee Ratios of Sectors (Box 5)
  - Medicaid (Box 5)
    - Title XX (Box 5)
    - Fee Profile (Box 5)
    - Overpayments (Box 5)
  - Advisory Committee-Medical Assistance Program Department of Social Services, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Letters Filed-A-N, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Letters Typed (Box 5)
    - A-N, 1982 (Box 5)
    - N-Z, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Commemorative Gifts Committee (Box 5)
  - Taxes (Box 5)
    - Old - 1960s (Box 5)
    - 1974 (Box 5)
    - Income Tax - Business - Corp. - P.A. (Box 5)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 5)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 5)
    - Income Tax - Personal, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Real Estate Associates Limited V (Box 6)
  - Leave Records (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Smith Barney Harris Upham (Box 6)
  - Blue Cross/Blue Shield - Family (Box 6)
  - W.B. Sanders Co. (Box 6)
  - Surgery History and Work-ups (Box 6)
  - Cataract Surgeries - Implants and Extractions (Box 6)
  - Contact Lens (Box 6)
  - Disability Insurance (Box 6)
  - Hill, Deborah (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Office Bills (Box 6)
  - Blue Cross/Blue Shield - Personal Care Plan (Box 6)
  - Alcon Laboratories (Box 6)
  - Ambulatory Surgical Center (Box 6)
  - Sashep Commission Report (Box 6)
  - Nursing (Box 6)
  - Joint Commission (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Finances (Box 6)
  - Employment - Fairweather (Box 6)
  - Meharry Medical College, (4 folders) (Box 6)
  - Academic Papers (Box 6)
  - National Medical Association, Inc., (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Newspapers (Box 6)
  - USAFSAM (Box 6)
  - Durham Community House, Inc. (Box 6)
  - Glaucoma (Box 6)
  - Duke Eye Center (Box 6)
  - Clark College (Box 6)
  - NC Medical Society (Box 6)
  - Durham County Hospital (Box 6)
  - National Society to Prevent Blindness (Box 6)
  - Letters, 1977 July-December, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Letters, 1977 January-June, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Letters, 1978, (1 of 3 folders) (Box 6)
  - Letters 1978, (cont. 2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Professional Organizations/Institutions (Box 7)
    - North Carolina CentralUniversity (Box 7)
    - Meharry Medical College (Box 7)
    - Greensboro College (Box 7)
    - Sigma Pi Phi, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - The Human Betterment League of NorthCarolina (Box 7)
    - North Carolina Joint Council of HealthEducation (Box 7)
    - National Society to PreventBlindness (Box 7)
    - Old North State, North Carolina MedicalSociety (Box 7)
    - National Medical Association (Box 7)
    - Durham County General (Box 7)
  - Medical/Professional Files (Box 7)
    - Medical Secretary's Forms Manual and Magazine (Box 7)
    - State of North Carolina Department of DisabilityDetermination (Box 7)
    - Nursing Class (Box 7)
    - Medicare (Box 7)
  - Financial, Insurance, Tax, and Property Files (Box 7)
    - [Checkbook records] (Box 7)
    - Medical Mutual Insurance (Box 7)
    - Medical Associates Inc. (Box 7)
    - North Carolina Department of Revenue (Box 7)
    - Medical Insurance Agency (Box 7)
    - A Physician's Guide to Gearing up for Retirement, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Dawson, Watts, and Cleland, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Dawson, Watts, and Cleland, 1971 (Box 7)
    - Dawson and Watts, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Dawson and Watts, 1977 (Box 7)
    - Dawson, Watts, and Cleland, 1977 (Box 7)
    - Century Oaks Contracts, Phase I, 1980 July (Box 7)
    - [Shelter Properties] (Box 7)
  - Printed Materials (Box 7)
    - Newspaper, Magazine, and Journal articles, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - [Personal Interest] (Box 7)
  - Professional Organizations/Institutions (Box 8)
    - NC Central University, (3 folders) (Box 8)
    - [Meharry Medical College], (3 folders) (Box 8)
    - [Old North State] (Box 8)
    - [National MedicalAssociation] (Box 8)
  - Professional/Medical Files, (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Financial, Tax, Insurance, and Property Files, (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Printed Material (Box 8)
    - Newspaper, Magazine, and Journal articles, (5 folders) (Box 8)
  - Financial, Tax, Property and Insurance Files (Box 9)
    - Dawson, Watts, and Cleland, 1972-1975, (4 folders) (Box 9)
    - Dawson and Watts, 1971-1975, (5 folders) (Box 9)
    - Retirement Plan/Profit Sharing plan, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Professional Organizations/Institutions (Box 9)
    - National Medical Association (Box 9)
  - Medical/Professional Files (Box 9)
    - Commission for the Blind, (5 folders) (Box 9)
  - [Speeches] (Box 9)
  - Printed Material (Box 9)
  - Sigma Pi Phi (Box 10)
  - Finances (Box 10)
  - Warren Lockhart TV Sports (Box 10)
  - Alexander&Associates Realty, Inc., (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Beverage Industry (Box 10)
  - Tax Returns, 1970s (Box 10)
  - Greeting Cards (Box 10)
  - [Miscellaneous/Loose Material], (5 folders) (Box 11)
  - Financial/Real Estate (Box 12)
    - [ Century Oaks, Ltd.], 1977-1981, (3 folders) (Box 12)
    - Blank income sheets for R. E. Dawson, M.D.P.A. (Box 12)
  - [Loose material: newspaper clippings] (Box 12)
  - Tintype of unidentified woman in [wedding dress], undated (Opaperfolder 1, Box 12)
  - 1997 African-American Heritage Calendar (Box 12)
  - Summary of expenses, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Oversize Material (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Opaperfolder 1, Box 12)
- Accession 2001-0153 (Box 12)
  - Contents of box 1: (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Information on Health Care (Box 1)
    - Payments (Box 1)
    - IRA (Box 1)
  - Contents of box 2: (Box 2)
    - Banking Information including statements, investments, and accounts (Box 2)
    - Insurance (Box 2)
    - Incorporation of Dawson's practice (Box 2)
  - Contents of box 3: (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Banking Information (Box 3)
    - Insurance (Box 3)
    - Investments (Box 3)
  - Contents of box 4: (Box 4)
    - Incorporation of Dawson's practice (Box 4)
    - Bills to Patients (Box 4)
    - Clark College (Box 4)
    - Letters typed and filed, A-M, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Contents of box 5: (Box 5)
    - Medicaid and Medicare (Box 5)
  - Contents of box 6: (Box 6)
    - Medical Associations and Societies (Box 6)
  - Contents of box 7: (Box 7)
    - Savings (Box 7)
    - Receipts (Box 7)
  - Contents of box 8: (Box 8)
    - Subject Files: O-P (Box 8)
  - Contents of box 9: (Box 9)
    - Subject Files: P-S (Box 9)
  - Contents of box 10: (Box 10)
    - Subject Files: S-V (Box 10)
  - Contents of box 11: (Box 11)
    - Subject Files: A (Box 11)
  - Contents of box 12: (Box 12)
    - Subject Files: B-F (Box 12)
  - Contents of box 13: (Box 13)
    - Subject Files (Box 13)
      - G-H (Box 13)
      - M (Box 13)
  - Medical Insurance (Box 13)
  - Medical Associations (Box 13)
  - Contents of box 14:, Subject Files: M (Box 14)
  - Contents of box 15:, Insurance (Box 15)
  - Magazines and Journals (Box 15)
  - Masons (Box 15)
  - Multiple Miscellaneous Files (Box 15)
    [possibly subject files]
  - Contents of box 16:, Harris Corporation (Box 16)
  - Greensboro College (Box 16)
  - Subject files: B-D (Box 16)